# Xing Li

5205 SW 99th Ave, Jasper, Florida | +1 206 395 3072 fencer.dev.9203@gmail.com

## **Summary**

After graduating with my Master's degree in Computer Science, I've spent the last 9+ years building professional experience in web development.

I am a highly-skilled Full Stack Engineer with a broad and versatile coding skill set.

I design and develop intuitive and feature-rich user-friendly solutions.

I have extensive knowledge of front-end JavaScript and browser APIs as well as significant experience with popular frameworks and libraries like React and Redux. My deep full-stack experience includes Node.js and Express, MongoDB as well as more traditional technologies like PHP, ASP.NET, and MySQL.

I am a go-to guy for any of your development needs.

### Experience

# Upcreatives | Shanghai, Shanghai Full Stack Developer | 04/2017 - Present

- Created completely serverless client-side local-first apps with React and TypeScript.
- Architected/developed the Node.js-based API server (combined REST-like and GraphQL) and worker services for the project back-end side.
- Constructed middleware that allowed React to work with our proprietary model framework.
- Built and analyzed an ad exchange platform with React/Angular frameworks.
- Added server-side rendering for the web part of the system with Next.js.
- Implemented Next.js/React-based app hosted on Google Firebase.
- Supported and improved the iflix user engagement platform written in Node.js, TypeScript, Express.js, and Nest.js using REST for communication.
- Created and improved microservices to support sending special offers to users via the user engagement platform using Node.js, TypeScript, Nest.js, Express.js, and REST.
- Worked on an experimental communications protocol with WebSockets using Node.js and JavaScript.

### Lantern Digital | Shanghai, Shanghai Full Stack Developer | 01/2014 - 05/2017

- Developed an all-in-one task management system using Vue.js and Node.js to allow users to create, delegate, and track their tasks, upload files, add comments, log history, etc. That reduced the overall task delegation time in an organization by 40%.
- Used Angular 5 and NgRx to make the Reactive front end.
- Migrated and merged an admin panel application into the platform.
- Built from scratch a product website with React and GatsbyJS.
- Built back-end APIs using Laravel best practice.
- Wrote many reusable Vue.js components using best practice.
- Managed server infrastructure at AWS (EC2, RDS, S3, SNS).
- Finished implementing a cryptocurrency exchange built using Angular.

## self-employed | Shanghai, Shanghai Software Engineer | 07/2013 - 02/2014

- Created a custom inventory tracker for the computer department using PHP and MySQL.
- Created a work order system for the maintenance department using PHP and MySQL.
- Created a reusable PHP utility library for projects.
- Upgraded and maintained websites to use more modern CSS, HTML, and jQuery widgets.
- Designed a new REST API that combined a client's existing MVC and Symfony components and customizations.
- Troubleshot and fixed browser CSS, JavaScript, and back-end logical bugs.

#### Skills

React, Redux, Angular, Node.js, Vue, PHP, Laravel, NextJS, NestJs, GraphQL, Vuex, Express, Typescript, webpack, Solidity, Rust, MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Amazon Web Services, GitHub, GitLab, Jest, C#

#### Education

Tsinghua University(THU) | Beijing, Beijing Computer Science and Technology | 09/2013 Master of Computer Science

# Languages

English